Finding Aid for Ecumenical Center and International Residence (University of Michigan) Records, 1947-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Ecumenical Center and International Residence (University of Michigan) Records, 1947-1999
Ecumenical Center and International Residence (University of Michigan)
13 lin. ft.
04106 Bimu 2
Campus ministry at the University of Michigan, sponsored by different congregations and denominations, community groups, and individuals and providing housing for international and U.S. students. Minutes, financial materials, correspondence, and other records of the Center and of its predecessor organizations.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were received from the Ecumenical Center (donor no. 9489 ) in August 2004.
The record group is open to research.
The Ecumenical Center and International Residence, a campus ministry at the University of Michigan provides housing for international and U.S. students. Sponsored by different congregations, denominations, community groups, and individuals, the Center was formerly called the Ecumenical Campus Center, which was established as a joint ministry of the Ecumenical Association for International Understanding (formerly known as the Protestant Foundation for International Students) and the University of Michigan Presbyterian Corporation.
This record group is arranged by record creator and by kinds of records. The series include: University of Michigan Presbyterian Corporation; Protestant Foundation for International Students; Ecumenical Association for International Understanding; Ecumenical Campus Center; and Other Records. The bulk of the records consist of minutes of meetings, financial information, and reports of programs. There is also an extensive set of newsletters, building campaign materials, and accumulated information from denominational bodies supporting the Center.
Subjects:
Ecumenical Center and International Residence.; Church work with students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Ecumenical Association for International Understanding.; Protestant Foundation for International Students (University of Michigan); Students, Foreign--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan. Presbyterian Corporation.; University of Michigan--Students.; University of Michigan--Student housing.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- University of Michigan Presbyterian Corporation (UMPC) records
  - Minutes, 1952-1972 (Box 1)
    (volumes with overlapping dates probably maintained by different officers)
    - 1952-1969, 8 volumes (Box 1)
      (some volumes also contain program reports, correspondence, and financial statements)
    - 1965-1970, 6 volumes (Box 2)
    - 1970-1972, 5 volumes (Box 3)
- Protestant Foundation for International Students (PFIS)
  - Photograph album, 1954-1955 (Box 3)
  - Minute book, 1947-1967 (Box 3)
    - 1947-1957 (Box 3)
    - 1957-1967, 6 volumes (Box 4)
- Ecumenical Association for International Understanding (EAIU) (successor to PFIS; name changed in June 1968)
  - Committee reports, 1965-1971 (Box 5)
    (volume covers both PFIS and EAIU activities)
  - Minute books, 1968-1972, 2 volumes (Box 5)
- Ecumenical Campus Center
  (being the joint ministry of the EAIU and the UMPC; a name later changed to Ecumenical Center and International Residence)
  - Record books, 1970-1994 (Box 5)
    - 1970-1974, 4 volumes (Box 5)
    - 1973-1986, 4 volumes and 2 folders (Box 6)
    - 1985-1989, 5 volumes (Box 7)
    - 1990-1994, 4 volumes and 1 folder (Box 8)
- Other records
  - Synod Committee on Campus Ministry in Michigan, 1978-1979 (Box 9)
  - Synod Committee on Ministry in Higher Education in Michigan, 1979-1980 (Box 9)
  - Presbytery of Southern Michigan, 1964-1966 (Box 9)
  - Presbytery of Detroit, 1975-1976 and 1980, 4 volumes (Box 9)
  - Newsletters, 1987-1999 (Box 10)
  - Unfoldered records (Box 11)
  - Building Fund Campaign Committee records (Box 12-13)